Attention.
I have an announcement to make.
The provincial results are in. I have
them here.
And I am proud to report that this year,
your marks in general are well
above average, with one or two
exceptions. And I am happy to say
that...
One student in particular has
distinguished herself.
Felicity King has been awarded one of
the highest grades in the province.
See, that's wonderful.
Settle down quietly, there is more good
news.
Kingsport Ladies College in Nova Scotia
has invited Felicity to
apply for a full scholarship there.
The finest school in the whole country.
Only the best girls go there.
Felicity, I'm so proud of you.
I can't believe it.
Kingsport Ladies College. You deserve
this scholarship, Felicity. How soon do
you leave? Felix.
Congratulations, Felicity.
Thank you, Gus. You're so lucky,
Felicity.
Imagine, Nova Scotia. Felicity, you're
bound to meet the best.
people. I know, I know. It's so
exciting.
You'll never want to come back here.
You'll be in real society.
What's the matter, Gus?
Nothing.
I have to know everything that there is
to know about polite society.
Felicity, it's just a school.
Oh, well, it's just the most prestigious
ladies' college in the Maritime.
And I've high hopes of you attending one
day, Sarah.
What are you looking for?
I have to be prepared, don't I? For
what?
For my interview.
Kingsport Ladies' College will expect
that I have knowledge in the appropriate
skill. Skills? What skill?
You know perfectly well what I'm talking
about, Sarah Stanley.
You've been schooled privately all your
life.
Now, the least you can do, as my cousin
and as my friend, is tell me the things
that I'll need to know to make a good
impression.
It's an outrage, that's what.
What's an outrage?
Percy Methley's hired a new chef.
A foreigner.
He's not a foreigner, Rachel. He's from
Quebec.
What did I tell you?
His name is Pierre Jean Lapierre.
Pierre?
I'm moving the foreign missions luncheon
to the Carmody Tea Room.
Now, Rachel, Percy Metley can hire any
fool he chooses.
Though, playing good English fare is the
mainstay of the White Sands Hotel, so
he's not likely to change that.
I like to identify what I'm eating,
that's what.
Did you hear that, Sarah?
French chef.
What?
How fortunate.
My souffle.
I need more tea right there, and the
lady's at number nine. One more.
I'm real sorry, Pierre.
I didn't even see you there.
I'll clean everything right up.
I do not tolerate incompetence.
You are here on probation.
Remember.
Keep an eye on you.
Oh, Sarah, I haven't a single thing to
wear.
All my clothes are so shabby.
There's this one. It's a little too big
for me. Beautiful.
Nanny Louisa sent it. Oh, I've never
seen a more perfect dress.
Well, you can borrow it if you like.
Oh, it looks simply ravishing.
The color suits you wonderfully.
Someday I'll have my own dresses from
Paris and a beautiful house with
to do my bidding.
Slow down, Felicity. You haven't even
been accepted yet. I will be.
What do you think of this one?
I've always liked it.
Well, I can't go with just one nice
dress.
I'm going to be there for at least four
days.
All right, then.
We can take down the hands on some of
these.
Oh, I knew you'd understand.
How else will I make a good impression
or make the acquaintance of the right
sort of people?
Very important to high academic
standings.
What?
Sarah, you've been lucky.
You've had all these sort of advantages.
This is the most important step I've
ever taken in my whole life.
You should be helping me.
You're right, Felicity.
I'll give you a few hints.
They never tell you about the real
qualifications.
What do you mean?
What qualifications?
Well, Sarah, you must tell me.
The other girls will all have been born
and bred to formal dinners with French
service. They'll all ride, shoot, skate,
sing opera, travel widely.
You'll have to do a lot of studying to
want to impress them.
Sarah, quickly. I need a pencil and
paper.
We must be logical about this.
Organized. Oh, there's so much to do.
You'll need expert advice.
But this is Avonlea.
I know.
We last... The new chef.
He'll be an expert.
He's French.
Natalie, can you help me with some of
these?
What's all this?
I borrowed some clothes from Sarah for
the interview.
Well, I was very thoughtful of Sarah.
Well, what's wrong with your own
clothes?
They're hardly suitable for Kingsport,
Father.
I'm not happy about this, Janet.
Well, she's just excited. She wants to
make a good impression.
That's impossible.
Felix.
I don't know.
Maybe this private school was the wrong
idea.
Oh, well, I think we should let Felicity
decide that, Alec.
It's a wonderful opportunity, and it's
important to her.
Now, I have a list of things that I must
find out about before I leave for
Kingsport tomorrow.
So I would like to be excused for my
chores this afternoon.
If that's all right with you, Mother.
Certainly, dear.
What sort of things?
Posture, etiquette, formal dining,
Italian opera.
Oh, well, Felicity, I'm... I'm sure
they'll be happy with you just the way
are. I want to be the best possible me.
That's why I've made up my little list.
I've noted my accomplishments on one
side and the areas in which I need
improvement on the other.
Well, you better let me see it, just in
case you lost something out.
There are children in my kitchen.
Get them out.
Shoo! Shoo!
Mr. Lapierre, I am Felicity King, and I
am desperate to know information that
only you can give me.
Really? Yes, but you see, the trouble is
I haven't much time, and old cuisine is
so very important to a thorough
education.
Oh, you're interested in fine food.
Yes, and since it's your specialty, I
thought you might like to help me.
I only need to know enough to get
through my interview.
And I leave tomorrow.
What? What?
You expect to learn in one afternoon
what it takes to the greatest of chefs
discover over a lifetime?
Well, it can't be that hard. After all,
it's only food.
Is there a problem?
Oh!
Come on, Felix, let's go.
What are you doing?
Felix, I'm sorry.
It just smelled so good and I was sort
of hungry.
I just thought I'd sample it.
It's good. What is it?
Onion de veau.
You like it?
Oh, yes.
What is it?
Kidneys.
And this?
great.
Hey, sir, try this.
No, thank you. I've never much cared for
cow's brains.
Long or sleep.
Delicious.
Maybe I overreacted to your friend.
I am very sorry.
A Frenchman tried to kill me, and Sarah
and Felix are still inside.
Well, he ain't too friendly, but a
warrant ain't exactly a
killer.
Now I'll be the only girl at Kingsport
without any knowledge of how to cuisine.
Well, I figure Kingsport ain't quite as
far as Paris.
Probably the same as we do.
Being a real lady, it's important to
you, ain't it? Good breeding and polite
manners are very important.
How else can one improve one's position
in life?
When are you going?
I leave tomorrow.
Felicity?
I'll be pulling for you.
Thank you, God.
Bye, Felicity.
was that again?
Eggs Benedict.
Pierre.
Pierre, this is the best darn egg I've
ever tasted in my life.
Emotional, isn't he?
Phoenix, you are the only civilized
person in all of Avonlea, all of Prince
Edward Island.
He wants you to go over there.
Need to talk to you.
What is it, Gus?
Some of us are trying to create magic
ici, Monsieur Pike.
Merci.
I need to learn manners, quick.
Telly day.
The wrist, Felix.
Manners? Yeah, I need the best there is.
What for?
Well, if good breeding and manners is
important, then I'm going to get them.
Manners? are for the guests, monsieur,
who are awaiting your services.
You're going to have to take something
out. I can't, Sarah. Everything is
essential. How many dresses do you have
in there? Six.
You're only going for four days.
Four and a half.
Besides, I can't wear the same thing
every day. What will they think?
Felicity, dear.
Tie up. Your father's waiting.
Felix, come on. We've already tried,
Daniel.
Felix and Sarah, come on.
There.
He's almost got it.
Here we go.
There's no need to be nervous.
I'm not.
But I do want you to be careful while
you're in Nova Scotia. I mean, it's not
like I don't want to leave you.
Yes, Father.
Now, someone's going to meet you at
Kingsport.
Yes. But I'm going to give you a couple
of extra dollars, just in case.
I'll be fine, Father.
I've been in a boat before.
I know. I know.
Father. Mm -hmm?
You and Mother really want me to go,
don't you?
Well, we want what's best for you.
I know.
I'll make you very proud of me.
I'm sure you'll adore KLC, Miss King.
Yes, I'm sure.
May I call you Felicity? Of course.
You must call me Agnes.
I can tell we'll become quite the best
of friends.
I'm sure we'll get along swimmingly.
Oh, yes.
Swimmingly.
Where are you from, Felicity?
Avonlea, Prince Edward Island.
I'm afraid I don't know it.
I was born in Tangiers.
Father and mother dragged us to England
early on, and then on to the continent,
before returning to Ottawa.
So I guess you might say I'm not really
from anywhere.
Really, King, the boy will sit here
begs.
Look.
That must be her.
Look at her coat.
Hello. Emily Everett Smythe from
Charlottetown. Margaret Fieldcrest from
Tavistock. Felicity King from Avonlea.
Where are your roommates?
I guess we're in competition for the
scholarship.
Avonlea. That's near the North Shore,
isn't it? Little farms with cows and
Charming. Here, let me take your coat,
Felicity. Thank you.
Your dress.
It's smashing.
Why, thank you.
It's from Paris.
All my clothes are from Paris.
Come along, girls.
Single file, please.
You girls come with me.
Good afternoon, girls.
For the benefit of our guests, who may
become one of us one day, my name is
Cavendish, and I am principal of
Kingsport Ladies College.
Kingsport Ladies College enjoys a
prestigious reputation which is well
preparing young women to take their
places in a civilized and polite
from the ballroom to the stateroom.
We expect that our girls will live up to
the honor of being a Kingsport lady.
Lovely evening, isn't it?
No, it ain't. Cold enough to freeze my
nose hair stuff.
Gus, it's an expression.
An introduction.
I don't mean it.
Well, if you don't mean it, why'd you
say it?
That's a good question.
I don't know why people say it. They
just do.
They say a lot of things they don't
mean.
It's too confusing.
I'll never get it right.
How could I ever go to that college and
ask for Felicity unless it was a
gentleman?
One more goal.
All right.
We'll start with compliments.
Now, you have to compliment everything.
What I'm wearing, my hair, the way I
laugh.
Got it.
Compliment everything.
Right.
My goodness, Sarah Stanley.
But that's a right pretty dress you're
wearing. And right pretty shoes and
stockings and... I guess that's about
it.
That's sort of the idea.
Well, that weren't too hard.
What's next?
Table manners.
Right.
No, no, no.
If it's the best manners that you want,
they'll have to be French.
It's big stuff now.
Do you intend to continue working here,
Mr. Pike?
Better get going, Sarah.
Took Mr. King three days to talk to Mr.
Matheline to give me my job back, and I
don't intend on losing it because of
some puffed -up old galley cook.
with a capital R, quite distinguished
from Romance, with a small r,
and yet again from the Romantics, with a
capital R,
which has nothing whatever to do with
the Romantics, lowercase.
Miss Peggy, see you at Harrods. See you,
Felicity. Have you ever been to London?
Yes. Yes, please. Black or white?
White, please. Aren't you afraid for
your weight? Where did you stay while
there?
Sugar? Yes, please.
Stay? Well, father always stays at the
Grosvenor in Belgravia.
Lemon?
Yes, please.
The Grosvenor? Yes.
Jam or marmalade?
Jam, please.
No any jam anymore.
Your dress.
My father's in shipping.
He spends most of his time in Toronto,
New York, and Montreal.
Margaret and I have been going to school
together for the past five years.
And your father's a senator, isn't he?
Well, so he claims.
Personally, I think he spends most of
his time chercher la femme.
They're all so beautiful.
So Parisian.
Yes. I shop on the Rue de Faubourg every
year.
You've been to Paris?
Many times.
I used to stroll down the Champs
-Élysées in the springtime when the
all in bloom.
Really? I thought you farm people
planted crops in the spring.
Courtesy of Daddy's humidor.
I wouldn't really know.
I'm not really a farm person.
But I heard Miss... Cavendish telling
Miss Wright that your parents are
people. My parents?
Oh, those people in Avonlea aren't
really my parents.
What do you mean?
My real parents lived in Montreal.
But my mother died when I was just a
baby.
That's terrible.
My father used to take me with him on
all his trips to Europe.
Until he died tragically.
It was at his warehouse.
He was crushed.
Oh, my.
I was staying with my aunt and uncle
grieving.
Until I was kidnapped.
Kidnapped? And held for ransom by a
crazy woman from a circus named Isis.
My uncle, at risk to his own life,
rescued me.
I owe him everything.
You've had such a romantic life.
I could tell right away that you weren't
raised on a farm.
My nanny Louisa sends me all the latest
fashions.
She remains our devoted family retainer
at my estate in Montreal.
Must be terrible for you to be stuck in
the country.
Well, they're not very wealthy or
sophisticated, but they're very kind to
What's the matter,
Pierre?
They only eat grease.
Eggs, fried. Bacon, fried.
Bread, fried. It makes my stomach turn.
Ventimals, boiled hummus.
Potatoes, like chalk.
Meat,
roasted to shoe leather.
Gravy? Wallpaper paste.
It's cruel.
It's inhuman.
It's inedible.
Problem is, that's always used to.
But it is impossible to educate their
palate.
You want over Felix there.
Absolutely. Felix is a boy of
exceptional taste.
He eats anything.
All you got to do is make it seem
familiar.
But how?
God, you're brilliant.
Him? Brilliant?
Just give your special plain English
names.
These eggs, for example.
My, uh, Florentine?
Yeah, them.
Just call them Eggs Avonlea style.
Well, that's right.
Give it a try, Pierre.
Hey, Gus Spike.
Why didn't you speak up sooner?
Save me all this aggravation.
I
heard
that a KLC girl has to have a broad
cultural background.
That puts you at a disadvantage, I
should think, Felicity.
Isolated in the country.
No concerts or plays or culture of any
kind.
But I've been to the Milan Opera
hundreds of times.
A father had a box there.
Friend of the Italian ambassador.
They're ready for you, Felicity.
Good morning, Miss King.
Good morning.
Sit down.
We're all very impressed by your
academic standing, Miss King. Thank you.
A KLC girl will have more than academic
excellence.
She is poised, graceful, with well
-rounded interest and accomplishment.
Miss King, are you a young woman who
would profit under our tutelage?
You want our girls to be la creme de la
creme. I see that you're accomplished in
piano.
Oh, yes.
I can play nearly every hymn in the
book.
Hymns?
Our girls are usually classically
trained musicians, Miss King.
Bach, Beethoven, Mozart.
Oh, well, of course.
Bach. I play Bach, of course.
What about sport?
Kingsport is renowned for its riding
academy.
Well, we have two horses at home.
I've ridden all my life.
I would like to know more about your
family.
I understand Mr.
and Mrs. King are not your real parents.
I heard the girls talking about it.
They're just like real parents.
They're wonderful people. I owe
everything to them.
Your gratitude and obvious love for them
do you credit?
Yes. Indeed.
And you've overcome disadvantages.
I like that.
Fish fork, fish knife, pallet fork,
sorbet spoon, entree fork, knife, spoon,
cake spoon, fruit service, teaspoon.
This is not a bin.
I want to thank you for coming to visit
us.
It's clear that each of you has
something special to offer Kingsport.
And I expect it's clear how Kingsport
could help prepare you for your foray
the world.
And although only one of you will be
selected for this year's scholarship,
I want to assure each of you that that
decision will be very
difficult.
As you all display attributes of a KLC
girl.
We will inform you of our decision as
soon as possible.
It's been a pleasure meeting you,
Felicity. You really must come to
Charlottetown for us. I wish we could
all attend KLC together.
We would have fun, wouldn't we?
Here she is.
Felicity!
Felicity King!
Glad you're back, Felicity.
How was it?
These your friends?
Anybody like a lift?
Felicity. Sarah, dear.
Gus, you can get my bag.
Your father said me and Sarah could come
and get you. Your father? I thought he
was dead, Felicity.
Uh, they like me to call them that.
Don't they, Sarah?
This is my sister, Sarah.
What? My classmates, Emily and Marcus.
Pleased to make your acquaintance.
I asked you to get my bag.
Pathetic, really. This country boy has a
mad crush on me.
It's very irritating.
Come on, Felicity, let's go.
But then don't speak. But you're being
very childish. We're being childish.
You're not the ones made up stories.
Stupid lies to impress people. I had to.
I will never win a scholarship coming
from such a common family.
There ain't nothing wrong with common
people.
You're just jealous.
Jealous of who?
I know those sort of girls.
They're cultured, sophisticated young
women.
And when I attend Kingsport, I intend to
become just like them.
Then for your own psycho sticking, I
hope you don't get in.
I'll remember that, Sarah.
I can manage it myself.
You needn't bother yourself with me any
longer.
Sorry, Gus.
I know she'll regret it.
That's what manners does to a person.
I don't want them.
Miss Lee, I'm absolutely dying to hear
all about King... Oh, Aunt Olivia, it
wonderful. I trust you conducted
yourself with all the dignity and
befits a king, did you? Of course, Aunt
Hattie. I would never do anything to
tarnish our family name.
You should have seen the grounds. They
were magnificent.
They have a stable full of horses, and
they teach equestrian riding and
dressage. Oh, and they have an enormous
greenhouse filled with exotic flowers
that are in bloom all year round.
Exotic flowers?
Whatever for?
Botany class.
All the girls are ever so friendly. They
come from the wealthiest and best
families in the country.
I'm going to meet some very important
and useful liaisons that will help me
the rest of my life.
Why, they embraced me as one of their
own.
Voila! Oh, my match.
I, uh, everyone.
Um, Felix made this himself.
Oh, well.
No.
Oh, Felicity.
Tell us all about the...
Howard went swimmingly.
Did I tell you I met a senator's
daughter?
Agnes Forbes.
And Emily Everett Smythe. Her father's
in shipping and they spend much of their
time in New York.
They are very wealthy.
We can certainly see what impresses you.
You promised me, Sarah.
Oh, my, my, Felix.
This looks interesting.
Looks like one of Jasper's experiments.
Oh.
What is it?
I call it escargot felix.
Really? And what exactly is escargot
felix?
It's snails in a garlic and butter
sauce.
Good.
Oh,
Felicity. I took the liberty.
It's from Kingsport.
Kingsport Ladies College is pleased to
inform you that you have passed the
initial interview.
You and your parents are scheduled
for... Well, Felicity.
She's overly excited.
Here, it says that...
You and Alec are to accompany Felicity
to Kingsport this Saturday.
Oh, the committee wishes to speak with
the parents as well as the candidates.
Oh, my goodness.
An interview.
But, Hattie, what'll I do?
What'll I say? What'll I wear?
Oh, it's just a say, very little, Janet.
You don't want to spoil Felicity's
greatest opportunity, do you?
Felicity, are you all right?
Oh, I'm fine.
It's just nerves.
A little nervous myself.
I want so much for you to be happy.
Your father and I are so proud of you.
We've always known you were clever and
special.
You have?
No, Felicity, dear.
No one could ask for a smarter, lovelier
daughter.
Sarah, what am I going to do?
They want to talk to my parents. Your
parents love you and care for you.
How could you do this to them?
It just happened. It wasn't my fault.
What am I going to say now?
I think you've said enough.
You just had to impress everyone, didn't
you?
Sarah, you have to help me.
You started it.
You loaned me your dresses.
I'm not getting out of this one,
Felicity King.
There's only one thing to do when you
know what that is.
Alec, all my clothing is inappropriate.
Whatever you wear, it'll be fine.
Well, I can't help thinking what those
other girls' mothers will be wearing. I
suppose I'll need my best shirt, huh?
Oh, what's the use? We look like a pair
of farmers.
We are farmers.
The vegetables are mush.
And the roast is like a piece of
leather.
And the gravy is like the consistency of
wallpaper paste.
This is cruel.
This is inhuman.
This is inedible.
Felicity, what is it?
Dear, you look unwell. Come here.
I do feel sick.
Oh, it's the scholarship business.
You'll be fine.
No, I won't.
Oh, Felicity.
Mother.
Father. I've decided.
I don't want to go to Kingsport.
What?
What brought this about?
I don't blame you if you hate me for the
rest of your lives.
Or if you banish me forever.
Will you just tell us what's happened?
I'm the worst daughter in the whole
world.
I just felt so inferior to all those
other girls.
And there I was in all of Sarah's
dresses.
And they thought that I was one of them.
And so I said that I was.
I pretended to be Sarah.
And I told them... I told them that you
weren't my parents.
You what?
I know that you'll never forgive me, and
I don't blame you.
I'll take any punishment. I deserve the
worst.
I'm so sorry.
Here, use this.
Oh, Alec.
Are we really so dreadful that she had
to pretend we weren't her parents?
It isn't about you.
You know Felicity.
She always has to be the best.
The other girls intimidated her.
daughter to disowning me.
Well, we'd better write to Mrs.
Cavendish and have to withdraw her name.
We'll do nothing of the sort.
Felicity, well, she's created this mess.
She's going to have to pay the piper.
Felicity?
Mother. Mother will never speak to me
again.
Well, I can't condone what you did.
But I just don't understand how the
bright, pretty,
self -assured girl I know could ever
feel that intimidated or inferior.
They just all knew so much more than me.
They had been so many places.
Well, as your Aunt Eddie likes to say,
talk is cheap.
Education is what makes the man or
woman.
Well, your whole life is an education in
who you are, who you will become.
And for you to be ashamed of us is to be
ashamed of yourself.
And I don't want you to ever feel like
that.
Oh, Father, I'm truly sorry.
I know, dear.
I think you should make amends.
How do you mean?
Well, you'll go to Kingsport to do that
interview.
And they will meet the real Felicity
King.
I want to begin by telling you what a
genuine pleasure it is to meet you.
Felicity has told us how kind you've
been to her.
We've heard that there's a great deal
that Felicity has told you.
Yes.
I disgraced myself before the committee.
And do not deserve the scholarship to
Kingsport Ladies College.
Whatever are you talking about,
Felicity?
The dresses I wore to the school
belonged to my cousin, Sarah.
I've never been to Paris.
I've lived in Avonlea all my life.
On the King farm.
With my parents.
Miss King, I never heard the like.
Why, Felicity?
I wanted the scholarship.
I thought I had to be as good as all the
other girls.
They all came from wealthy families,
private schools.
And all those questions about piano
lessons and figure skating, English
schools and orchids from South America.
I see.
I would like to withdraw my application.
I am not worthy to be a KLC girl.
Miss King.
What you did was very wrong.
But I see we owe you an apology as well.
Whatever for?
As you were speaking, I realized that
our criteria have become too narrow.
Beyond the grasp of most girls.
We may have lost our true aim, academic
excellence.
I had never heard of dressage or organs
until I came here.
You're obviously a fine girl, Miss King,
and we will accept your withdrawal from
next year's class.
But please, when you are ready to leave
Avonlea, we would be happy to consider
your application.
Yes, Mr. Cavendish.
What happened to you?
None of those clothes were mine.
And I've never even been to Paris.
Or anywhere else, for that matter.
I live on a farm.
And I attend a one -room schoolhouse
taught by my Aunt Hetty.
But I still beat both of you in academic
standing.
Felicity, are you ready?
Ready, Father.
Good day, ladies.
Well, I never.
Her mark's really better than yours,
Emily.
Look, there she is. What a snob. She
just found her own parents.
I'd like to do that sometimes.
Hello, Felicity.
How was Kingsport?
I hear things went swimmingly.
It was an education.
Going to Paris anytime soon? Talk is
cheap, Sally Potts.
And so are you.
That's my girl.
I don't want to talk to that Chef
Pierre.
He's from Trois -Rivières.
Come on. He's a chef extraordinaire.
Come on, Ruthie. He's really very nice.
Three orders of flank steak, Pierre.
Flank. Ah, buffet party.
Right away.
Bienvenue, les amis.
Miss Kang?
I don't blame you for being angry with
me, Gus.
May I show you to your table?
I behaved so badly, Gus.
I know what you tried to do.
I'm sorry about the scholarship,
Felicity.
I know it meant a lot to you.
I discovered it didn't mean as much as I
thought.
Here. Too much Dijon in the mingarette.
Phoenix, what would I do without you?